你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
欢迎回到我们关于如何使用Nano命令行文本编辑器获取工作的讨论
And welcome back to our discussion of how to use the Nano command line text editor to get your work
好了。
done.
在上一个视频中，我们讨论了Nano拥有的一些选项，我们讨论了
So we were in the last video we were discussing some of the options that Nano has and we discussed the
右-O选项，读选项，WHERE是选项，我们得到了REPLACE选项。
Right-O option the read option the where is option and we got up to the replace option.
因此，让我们实际使用Read Form选项再次读入生日文档文本。
So let's actually use the read form option to read in birthday doc text again.
所以我们要说生日，点文本，你看，我们生日快乐。
So we're going to say birthday Dot text and you see that we've got happy birthday.
再次读入文件。
Read into the file once again.
我这样做的原因是我们现在可以使用REPLACE命令，您可以在这里看到
And the reason I've done that is so that we can now use the replace command and you can see here that
REPLACE命令(尽管此处是REPLACE选项)是通过按Ctrl和反斜杠激活的。
the replace command although replace option here is activated by pressing control and a backslash.
现在我在键盘上找到了字母Zed旁边的反斜杠，但它可能在您的键盘上的任何位置
Now I find the backslash next to the letter Zed on my keyboard but it might be wherever that is on your
在您的计算机或键盘上。
on your computer or on your keyboard.
好的。
OK.
所以新闻控制和反斜杠。
So the press control and backslash.
现在它又问我想换什么。
And now it's asking me what I want to replace.
所以我们换个生日吧。
So let's replace birthday.
好的。
OK.
我们要把它换成代码日。
And we're going to replace it with code day.
当我按Enter键时，它现在将遍历找到单词生日的每个实例
And when I press Enter it's going to now go through each instance of where it found the word birthday
问问你要不要换掉它。
and ask if you want to replace it.
现在你可以在底部看到它，这是因为我确实想要放置这个实例，我可以说，是的，我
Now you can see it on the bottom here is because I do want to place this instance I could say yes I
我可以说“不”，也可以说“全部”，或者我可以说“控制”，然后看看是否取消。
could say no or I could say all or I could say control and see for cancel.
所以我们只需按下a键就可以将其全部替换掉。
So let's just press a to make it replace all.
我们看到，生日的每一个例子都被单词code day取代了。
And we see that every instance of birthday has been replaced with the word code day.
祝你代码日快乐，你这个漂亮的人。
So happy code day to you you beautiful person.
那就是替换文本，下一个就是剪切文本，剪切文本。
So that's replacing text what about cutting text cutting text is the next one.
所以切割非常容易，你可以看到这里有这样一行字，写着“代码日快乐”。
So cutting is very easy you can see here we've got this line that says Happy code day.
如果我按下Ctrl键和K键进行剪切，基本上就会删除该行，如果我想粘贴它的话。
If I press control and K to cut that basically deletes the line and if I want to paste that.
因此，基本上这就像是在日常电脑使用中剪切和粘贴一样。
So basically it's just like cutting and pasting just in your normal everyday computer use.
所以如果我想把它剪下来，我按下Ctrl，你和我可以想做多少次就做多少次。
So if I want to uncut it I press control and you and I can do that as many times as I want.
所以这是一个非常非常快乐的代码日。
So this is a very very happy code day.
我们还可以使用CONTROL和JS控件对齐文本，明显的nj，我们将看到文本已经
We can also justify the text using control and JS control obvious NJ we'll see that the text has been
设置使其占据整个屏幕的宽度，现在控制您不对齐。
set so that it takes up the full width of the screen are controlling you now to unjustified.
但是你可以看到，如果我按Ctrl，NJ来对齐文本，我的意思是，段落占据了整个段落
But you can see if I press control NJ to justify the text the paragraph that I mean takes up the full
屏幕和节育的正确上下文的宽度，您可以证明它是正确的。
width of the right context for with the screen and for birth control and you can justify it.
所以，如果你看一下控制J，你要记住的一些事情是合理的。
So something to bear in mind if you look at control J is justified.
在证明控件是合理的之前，您是未剪切的文本。
And before you justify control you is uncut text.
但是如果节育和J.
But if birth control and J.
您看，您现在已经将控件切换为调整类型，它告诉您，您现在可以调整控制
You see that control you has now switched to justify kind it tells you here you can now justify controlling
你。
you.
它又回到了以前的样子。
It goes back to the way that it was.
接下来我们有两个拼写选项，基本上是一个拼写检查器。
So up next we've got the two spell option which is basically a spell checker.
现在，默认情况下，没有为Nonno设置拼写检查器。
Now by default a spell checker isn't set up for Nonno.
所以如果我按Ctrl t，它会显示拼写检查失败，调用拼写错误，比如OK。
So if I press control t it will say spellchecking failed error invoking spell like OK.
这意味着实际上没有设置拼写检查器，但我们可以设置一个。
What that means is that there's a spell checker not actually set up but we can set one up.
因此，让我们通过按下0中的Ctrl来保存我们的文件来写入它。
So let's just save our file by pressing control in 0 to write it.
好的可以。
Yes that'll do.
然后按Ctrl X退出并使用Ctrl清除屏幕，l会看到许多键盘快捷键
And then press control X to exit and clear the screen with control and l see a lot of keyboard shortcuts
在这里进行。
going on here.
为了实际编辑文本，这是一种拼写检查器，用于NONNO，它位于
So to actually edit the text they that's sort of a spell checker that is used for Nonno that's in the
Nano配置文件，它实际上位于我们的ETSI文件夹中的一个名为Nano或C的文件中，因此
Nano configuration file which is actually located in our ETSI folder in a file called Nano or C so that's
用Nano打开并不是很讽刺，因为如果我们这样做，我们现在已经打开了我们的Nano Ossy
open not really ironically with nano because if we do that here we are we've now opened our nano Ossy
这就是劈开ATC劈开纳米奥西。
So it's slash ATC slash nano Ossy.
因此，如果我以图形方式向您显示我们要去哪里，我们将转到其他位置，从而在我们的基目录中
So if I show you that graphically where where we're going we are in our base directory by going to other
我想是地点。
location I think.
这就是劈开文件夹。
So this is the slash folder.
然后你去ATC。
Then you go ATC.
所以懒散的UTC，那么在这里的某个地方，会有一个叫做“无”的文件，我们没有人看到这一点。
So sloshy UTC then somewhere in here there'll be a file called none and none of us see this.
如果我们点击NORC，那基本上就是我们打开的。
If we click on NORC that's basically what we've opened.
好的，但是我们要确保我们在这里打开它。
OK but let's make sure that we open it in in here.
好的。
OK.
实际上，在那一刻，这个文件实际上是在Ridable上，因为我们没有波斯人来编辑它。
Actually at the minute this file is in fact on ridable because we don't have the Persians to edit it.
所以为了使它真正可编辑，我们需要做伪纳米懒散的UTC劈开纳米RC。
So to make that actually editable we need to do pseudo nano sloshy UTC slash nano RC.
好的，据称运行此命令的伪裸基本用户是管理员，但我们将继续讨论这一点
OK so this pseudo bare basic alleged to run this command is the administrator but we'll come onto that
课程后面会有更多的内容。
a bit more later in the course.
您可以输入通常用于登录的密码。
You enter your password that you normally use for logging in.
现在您可以编辑该文件了。
And now you can edit the file.
好的。
OK.
现在这里有一行字，里面有咒语或咒语。
Now there's a line in here that has the word a spell or spell in it.
因此，让我们通过使用WHERE is Command表示WHERE is Aspell按Enter来找出这一点。
So let's find that by using the where is Command says where is aspell press enter.
它找到了它。
And it found it.
好的。
OK.
这里的这一行说，使用这个拼写检查器，而不是内部的拼写检查器。
So this line it says here use this spelling checker instead of the internal one.
此选项没有正确的默认值。
This option does not properly have a default value.
好的，要去除它，要真正实现它，我们只需要去除这个散列
OK so to get rid of that actually to make that actually happen we just need to get rid of this hash
符号并去掉前导空格。
symbol and get rid of the leading space.
现在没有散列了，只是设置了Spella。
Now there's no there's no hash just set Spellar.
我拼写的Dash狂喜就是这样。
I spell dash ecstasy just like that.
然后我们写出并结案。
And we write out and close.
现在，如果我们回到Nano来获取日记文本，如果我们按Ctrl和t来实际停止咒语
And now if we go back into nano for our diary text if we press control and t to actually stop the spell
我们现在有一个拼写检查器在工作，所以这不是很酷，对吧，我们只是用Nonno来编辑Nonno。
checker we now have a spell checker working so it's not quite cool right we just use Nonno to edit Nonno.
太棒了。
It's awesome.
所以我们来了。
So here we are.
它正在接受拼写检查，它告诉我我的名字是错的。
It's going through a spell checker is telling me my name is wrong.
那真是太迷人了，不是吗？
Well that's charming isn't it.
这就对了。
There you go.
这就是您可以实际开始设置拼写检查器的方式，您只需在
That's how you can actually go about setting up your spell checker and you can just enter things in
这里。
here.
所以如果我想改名为尤达，我当然会这么做。
So if I wanted to change my name to let's say Yoda which of course I do.
因为那太棒了。
Because that's totally awesome.
我刚输入5，你会看到我现在的名字是尤达，这是事实，因为它在视频上。
I just enter five and you see that my name is now Yoda and it's a fact because it's on a video.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我现在走了，我还可以让一个人接近这些奥特曼人中的任何一个，你可以忽略替换Agta字典
So if I now go I can also close a human to any of these Otterman you can ignore replace Agta dictionary
并全部替换或忽略全部或任何可能的内容。
and replace all or ignore all or whatever it might be.
但我们只需按X键退出，我们就可以回到正常状态了。
But let's just press X to exit and there we are we're back into normal stuff.
所以一旦你编辑好了，你要做的就是等你的拼写检查器正常工作的时候再去做，这样你的拼写检查器就可以正常工作了
So once you've edited that all you've got to do it when you get to that so that your spell checker works
现在就可以开始了，还可以添加不同的字典和诸如此类的东西
you're good to go and it is possible to to also add different dictionaries and stuff like that as well
你也可以在网上找到这些信息。
and you can find that information online as well.
好的，我们就是这样做拼写检查和控制的，显然这会告诉你你的
OK so there we are that's how you do spellchecking and control and see is apparently tells you your
现在的位置如果我按下Ctrl键，他们会告诉我们我在95%中的第1条线上
current positions if I press control and say they will tell us I'm on line 1 out of ninety five percent
从第一列到第70列，共275个字符中的0个。
of the way through column one to 70 characters 0 out of 275.
如果我现在移到这里，按Ctrl键，然后说change，我现在在第7行，第10列。
So if I move over here now and I press control and say change I'm now on line 7 column 10.
所以对我们来说，这是很好的，你知道，如果你正在处理一个文件，你想把它交给某人
So for us this is this is good you know if you are working on a file and you want to give it to someone
然后你说，哦，嘿，你能在这个给定的位置更改这个文件吗，或者你在给人们指示
and you say Oh hey can you change this file at this given position or you're giving people instructions
关于如何使用您在第11栏中所说的Online 7的文件，请更改此文本。
on how to use a file you say online 7 in column 11 change this text.
好的。
OK.
所以实际上只是为了展示一下，让我把它保存起来。
So in fact just to show you let me let me actually save that.
是。
Yes.
如果我去任何劈开、ETSI、劈开、NONO或C文件，我都能搜索到那个拼写在哪里。
If I go to any slash ETSI slash Nonno or C file and I can search for where is that a spell.
现在我可以告诉你，我被咒语迷住了，如果我按下Ctrl键，我可以看到我在第172行。
Now I can tell you I'm on a spell and if I press control and see I can see here that I'm on line 172.
因此，如果您想设置拼写检查器，请转到第172行，这是您需要编辑的行。
So if you want to set your spell checker go to line 172 and that's the line that you need to edit.
例如，这将是正确做这件事的一种方式。
For example that would be one way to do it right.
这样我就可以结束它，回到直接的文本中。
So I can close that get back into the direct text.
现在我们正在通过下一个选项是控制和得分以下，这让我们可以走到一条线上。
Now we're getting through the next option is control and under score and that allows us to go to a line.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我在范围上按下Ctrl键，然后先控制下划线。
So if I press control on the scope and first control the underscore.
哦，对不起，我按错了按钮。
Oh sorry I'm pressing the wrong button here.
我们开始了，因为它只是放在我的电脑上一个有点奇怪的位置，控制着我的电脑。
There we go because it just goes in a bit of a weird position on my computer so controlling.
他说输入行号和列号。
And he says enter the line number and column number.
那么让我们转到10号线。
So let's go to line 10.
第二列，然后我们在第十行，看看我能不能让这个东西变得更大一点。
Column 2 and then we are in line 10 column to see if I can actually get this stuff to get a bit bigger.
好了，我把字体调大了一点。
There we go I've made the font a bit bigger.
所以对分数的控制做到了，因为我必须按下Ctrl和Shift，并下划线，我们开始了
So control on the score done it because I have to press control and shift and underscore there we go
反正是我的。
on mine anyway.
所以现在你要做一个行号和列号，或者比方说第9行，第12列。
So so now you're going to do a line number and column numbers or let's say Line 9 column 12.
我们走吧。
There we go.
我们在伊凡列上排队，不是用空格分隔的，用字母隔开的。
We are in line on Ivan columns aren't separated by spaces separated by letters.
好的。
OK.
这是他的专栏12，3，4，5，6，7，8，9，10，11，12。
So here are his column 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12.
好的。
OK.
这就是我们现在所处的位置，如果你想把它叫做12，不管是哪条线，我们都可能得到两个。
That's that's where we are this way we might get two if you want to call it 12 on whatever line.
所以如果我对你说让我们问问劈开ETSI劈开非战争是秋天，我在找使用的地方
So if I said to you let's ask Slash ETSI slash non-war was fall and I looked for using using the where
是命令。
is command.
我确实控制了B，我搜索了一个咒语，然后我就到了这条线。
I do control the B and I search for a spell and I get to this line.
我就像是。
I'm like Huh.
这条线在哪里？
Where is this line.
控件并查看哪个是合成。
Control and see which is composition.
上面写着172号线。
It says Line 172.
好的，现在在你们的电脑上。
OK so now on your computer.
好的。
OK.
当您打开该文件时，您会看到类似haZ的内容，并显示第172行剩余控制，并在行中加下划线
When you open the file you get like ha Z and says Line 172 surplus control and underscore into line
172按Enter键。
172 press enter.
我已经走到了正确的路线上，所以你们可以看到，如果你们合作的话这可能会有多大的用处
And I've ended up at the correct line so you can see how useful that might be if you're collaborating
和某人一起做某事。
on something with someone.
所以让我们回到我们的日记胶带上吧。
So let's get back into our diary duct tape.
然后我们有撤消和重做。
We've then got undo and redo.
所以，举个例子，如果我把这里所有的东西都剪掉，然后我就会说，哦，我不想要那个。
So if I for example cut out all these things here and then I was like oh I don't want that.
让我解开。
Let me undo.
你可以看到，我只是撤销，它撤销了所有的漂白，我也可以按Olt，记住这可以
You can see I just undo and it undid all those bleatings I could also press Olt and remember this could
是转义还是命令取决于您的键盘布局和Modify键，不管它是用来做什么的
be escape or command depending on your keyboard layout and just the modify key whatever that is for
你。
you.
在我的键盘上是旧的，但是如果我按ALT，我们应该重做阿尔坦，你可以撤销重做奥尔森。
On my keyboard it's old but if I press alt and we should redo Altan you undo redo Olson.
奥尔顿，你。
Alton you.
对，对。
Yeah yeah.
我现在把它弄坏了，不过你明白我的意思。
I've broke it now but you get the point.
所以。
So.
所以这就是你撤销和重做东西的方式。
So that's how you can undo and redo stuff.
你能不能看看我能不能。
And instead of cutting Could you see if I could.
现在我可以取消裁剪而不是裁剪了。
Now I can uncut instead of cutting.
你实际上可以直接复制。
You can actually just directly copy.
所以在这里你要做所有的事。
So here you've got to do all.
6代表印刷机终极号码6。
And the number 6 for press ultimate number 6.
现在我可以按下你的控制键，我会开始粘贴，所以如果我在这里做，奥尔顿就6岁了，然后
Now I can press control in you and I'll start pasting so maybe if I if I do it here Alton's 6 and then
按下你身上的控制键。
press control on you.
现在我正在复制和粘贴，就像这样。
Now I'm copying and pasting just like that.
因此，据我所见，这将使您不必实际剪切和标记文本。
So that saves you from actually cutting and Mark text as far as I've seen.
我不经常用那个，但据我所知，它能做的就是让你突出显示一些东西
I don't use that one very often but as far as I can tell all that does is allow you to highlight stuff
所以，是的，它只是让你可以突出一些东西。
so yeah it just it just kind of allows you to highlight stuff.
所以我们走吧。
So there we go.
这基本上就是关于使用Nano命令需要知道的所有内容，所以你们是漂亮的人
That's basically everything you need to know about using the Nano command so you are you beautiful people
在最后几个视频中，您将非常熟悉使用基于Nano命令行的文本编辑器。
in the last couple of videos you become very familiar with using the Nano command line based text editor.
现在，使用基于命令行的文本编辑器(如Nano)的好处是，您可以获得所有
Now the benefit of using a command line based text editors such as nano is that you can get all of your
无需离开命令行即可完成工作，这基本上可以最大限度地提高您的工作效率。
work done without leaving the command line which basically maximizes your productivity.
它是一种命令行编辑器，与图形等效项相比，对资源的要求较低，因此您不需要
It's a command line editors have lower resource requirements than graphical equivalents so you don't
需要尽可能多的硬件使用量才能真正运行它们。
need as much hardware usage in order to actually run them.
另外，如果您正在远程管理服务器之类的东西，那么您在这里学到的技术将
And also if you are remote administering something like a server the techniques you've learnt here would
仍然可以使用，因为Nano基本上随Linux的每个版本一起提供，至少是最常见的版本。
still work because nano basically comes with every version of Linux at least the most common ones anyway.
您已经学习了如何使用Nano，我们已经研究了很多键盘快捷键选项，您可以看到
So you've learned how to use nano and we've looked at a lot of keyboard shortcut options and you saw
如何使用，以及几乎所有这些。
how to use and pretty much all of those.
所以你不需要记住它们，不用担心，现在你已经有了一点想法
So you don't have to memorize them don't worry about that now you've got a bit of an idea about how
它们起作用了。
they work.
老实说不是，我只是个文本编辑。
Honestly not I was just a text editor.
您只需在其中键入文本，您可以在其中编写任何您想要做的代码，您还可以对其进行编辑
You can just type text in there you can write code in there whatever you want to do and you can edit
文件在里面。
files in there.
但请记住，这些工具中的选项是使用键盘快捷键访问的。
But just bear in mind that the tools are the options in there are accessed using keyboard shortcuts.
如果你看到这顶小帽子，那就是控制键。
So if you see this little hat then that means the control key.
如果您看到减号，键盘上的旧转义键或命令键取决于您的
And if you see minus that either the old escape or command keys on your keyboard depending upon your
布局以试用它们，看看哪一个可以在您的键盘上工作。
layout to try them out see which one works on your keyboard.
在我的身上，你的身上可能会有所不同。
On mine it was all it might be different on yours.
您还可以看到，您可以通过编辑Nano的配置文件来编辑Nano的工作方式，该配置文件位于
And you also saw that you can edit how nano works by editing its configuration file which is located
在劈开ETSI劈开纳米或C.
at slash ETSI slash nano or C.
其中很多内容可能是供您参考的，因此您可以在这个视频中找到这些内容
So a lot of this stuff is going to be probably for reference for you so you've got it here in this video
在本课程中，如果您想查找任何内容，请稍后再参考。
in this course to refer back to later on if you want to look anything up.
但实际上，Nano很容易让你输入Nano，然后他们发现你想要编辑。
But really Nano is very simple to use you to type Nano and then they found that you want to edit.
你知道你可以像编辑任何其他文本文件一样去编辑它。
And you know you can just go and edit it like any other text file.
因此，您知道如何结束它，这是从命令行开始的，您应该会觉得
So there you are you know know how to end it follows from the command line and should be feeling quite
更像是电脑巫师。
a lot more like a computer wizard.
在这一点上。
At this point.
因此，随着所有这些超级棒的文件创建、移动、复制、粘贴和编辑，您将执行这些操作。
So with all this super awesome file creation moving copying and pasting and editing that you'll be doing.
您可能需要查找某些重要配置文件的位置，因此
It's possible that you might want to find where certain important configuration files are located so
你可以编辑它们，或者乌克兰要去哪里，但你不想去
that you can edit them or where that fall that Ukraine is run off to but you don't want to have to go
手动浏览每个文件夹以查找它们。
through each folder manually to look for them.
在下一个视频中，您将学习如何使用
So in the next video you're going to learn how to search for files anywhere on your system using the
定位命令定位命令是我的最爱之一，我迫不及待地想给你看。
locate command locate command is one of my favorites and I can't wait to show you.
所以对于所有这些好东西。
So for all that good stuff.
我将在下一个视频中见到你。
I'll see you in the next video.